One man. One masterpiece. One very big mistake.
Bean is a family, adventure, comedy film directed by Mel Smith.
Childlike Englishman, Mr.
Bean, is an incompetent watchman at the Royal National Gallery.
After the museum's board of directors' attempt to have him fired is blocked by the chairman, who has taken a liking to Bean,
they send him to Los Angeles to act as their ambassador for the unveiling of a historic painting to humiliate him.
Fooled, Mr.
Bean must now successfully unveil the painting or risk his and
a hapless Los Angeles curator's termination.
Mr. Bean, played by Rowan Atkinson.
David Langley, played by Peter MacNicol.
Alison Langley, played by Pamela Reed.
Jennifer Langley, played by Tricia Vessey.
Kevin Langley, played by Andrew Lawrence.
George Grierson, played by Harris Yulin.
Bean is a 1997 British comedy film directed by Mel Smith and written by
Richard Curtis and Robin Driscoll, based on the British sitcom Mr.
The film stars Rowan Atkinson as Mr.
Bean, with Peter MacNicol, Pamela Reed, Harris Yulin
and Burt Reynolds in supporting roles.
In the film, Bean works as a security guard at the National Gallery in London before being sent to the United
States to talk about the unveiling of James Abbott McNeill Whistler's 1871 painting Whistler's Mother.
Bean was released in Australia on 3 July 1997, and
in the United Kingdom on 1 August.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a box-office
success, grossing $251 million against a budget of $18 million.
A sequel, Mr.
Bean's Holiday, was released in 2007.
The film explores themes of california, london,
england, airport, paris, france, chaos.
The tone is lighthearted.